# 昨天 昨天抓那個魚沒抓到 今天我帶抽水機去
Yesterday, yesterday we tried to catch some fish but couldn’t. I’m going with the water pump today,
# 把那水全部抽乾
and drain all the water.
# 那裡太深啦 我都沒想到 竟然有1米多深
It’s too deep there. I didn’t expect that. C’mon, it’s a metre deep.
# 里面很多魚的哦
There are a lot of fish inside, you know.
# 把那抽水機抬上去
Let’s carry the water pump up there,
# 直接把它抽啦
and drain the ponds right away.
# 小豬
Piggies!
# 你們也這拱那拱 是不是
You guys are also snorting here and there, aren’t you?
# 不要教壞了你
Don’t learn from a bad example!
# 這個終於把它搬上來啦
Finally, we've carried it here.
# 這個抽水機都壞啦 就這個頭子壞啦
This water pump doesn’t work. This opening is broken.
# 要不然就可以抽得到水的 現在都抽不到啦
Otherwise, I should be able to drain the water. But it’s impossible now.
# 白搞一場 我去下面把那個大水池放啦 放水
It wastes my time. I’m gonna drain, drain the water in the pond down there.
# 捉點魚 晚上來吃
I wanna catch some fish, for dinner.
# 不然都沒魚吃啊
Otherwise I’ll have no fish tonight.
# 衣服都搞濕啦
I’ve even got my clothes wet.
# 一條魚都沒有 怎麼行
Not even one fish. It’s unacceptable.
# 走走走走走 把這個帶回去 走走
Go, go, go, go, go! Let me take this one with me. Let’s go!
# 裝好來 下次 抽水機放在這裡 過兩天我再拿
Pack everything! Next time... Leave the water pump here. I’ll take it back a couple of days later.
# 你看 這個池塘 快一年都沒有放水了哦
Have a look at this pond. It has almost been a year since our last time draining it.
# 裡面魚都長大啦
Now the fish inside have already grown up.
# 上面那個 抽水機都搞壞啦
The ponds, up there... The water pump was even broken there.
# 放個 我放這個 這個很好放的
I’m, I’m gonna drain this one. It’s so much easier.
# 在這裡 直接一放就可以
Here, it can be drained right away.
# 你看 這個開關一放就可以啦 很簡單的
Look! Open the valve here. That’s it. Suer simple!
# 抽水機都不用
No water pump needed.
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 這還有一個開關
Here’s another one.
# 這叫雙劍合壁
One plus one is not just two.
# 放得就更快 這樣
Now it’s much quicker, then.
# 兩個 兩個開關
Two, two valves
# 快吧 這樣
It’s really quick, isn’t it?
# 兩個管子一起放
Water is now coming out from both pipes.
# 這裡放一個
Here’s one more.
# 就個就比較慢一點
But this one is a bit slower.
# 這水都開不乾的
The water just can’t be completely drained
# 撈一下
Let me try to catch.
# 撈一下 哎喲
Let me try. Ayo!
# 有 有魚待在這裡面
I know, I know that there are fish.
# 都放了好多魚下去 怎麼沒啦
I’ve also put a lot of fish here. Why isn't here any fish now?
# 哎呀 好滑呀
Aya! It’s so slippery.
# 哎呀 你幹嘛
Aya! What are you doing?
# 嚇我的
You scared me.
# 就你 跳得最高
You jump the highest. So you’re chosen.
# 你看 那裡有一條魚
Look! There's a fish.
# 它肚子好大呀
It has a very big belly.
# 放啦 放啦 不要
Let it go, let it go. I’m not taking it.
# 肯定是有崽啦
There must be babies inside.
# 把它放啦 不要啦
Let it go. We're not taking it.
# 我去抓上面的 上面更漂亮
I’m gonna catch those up there. Those are much prettier.
# 你看 這那麼紅 肯定不好吃
Look! It’s so red. It can’t be tasty.
# 下次我抓上面那 那幾條來
Next time I’m gonna catch those up there. I’ll catch a couple of them.
# 你自由啦 你肚子那麼大
You’re free now. You have such a big belly.
# 應該是有 有崽啦
There should be, should be babies.
# 等抽水機好了的時候我再上面那邊
I’ll go up there again when the water pump is fixed.
# 把那個魚抽下來 它那個魚比較好吃
Drain the water and catch the fish there The fish there taste better.
# 這個自己家養的不好吃
My own fish here don’t taste good.
# 好啦 我把水堵一下
Alright! Let me shut the valves.